Guide to the Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
1898-1953.
Mitchell, Wesley C. (Wesley Clair), 1874-1948.
22.5 linear ft. (ca. 24,000 items in 49 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079117
Series I: Economic Theory and its History
Series II: Business Cycles
Series III: Correspondence
Series IV: Printed Material
Series V: P-WCM Published Material by WCM
Series VI: M Money, The Money Economy, and Economic History
Series VII: N National Planning
Series VIII: O Anthropology and Psychology
Series IX: Miscellaneous
Series X: Wesley Clair Mitchell 1998 Addition
Biographical Note
American economist, teacher. Professor of economics at Berkeley, 1903-1912, and at Columbia University, 1913-1919 and 1922-1944; a founding faculty member of the New School for Social Research, 1919-1922; and the founder and director of the National Bureau of Economic Research, 1920-1945. In 1912, he married Lucy Sprague, educator and founder of Bank Street College of Education.
Scope and Content
Professional correspondence, diaries, unpublished articles, lecture notes, abstracts, and other manuscripts by Mitchell. Subjects include economic theory and its history, business cycles, money, national planing, anthropology and psychology, and published material by Mitchell and others.
Abbreviations:
AAAS American Association for the Advancement of Science
AEA American Economic Association
ASA American Statistical Association
BASM The Backward Art of Apending Money
BC Business Cycle; (13) denotes 1913 volume, (27) denotes 1927 volume
BC "Business Cycles" course
BCU Business Cycles and Unemployment
EC "Economic Change" course
EH "Economic History" course
EO "Econimic Origins" course
GPW Gold, Prices, and Wages under the Greenback Standard
HG A History of Greenbacks
HP History of Prices Dirung the War
ILO International Labor Organization
ISI International Statistical Institute
LSM Lucy Sprague Mitchell (wife)
M "Money" course
MBB Measuring Business Cycles
ME "Money Economy" course
MUNI Making and Using Index Numbers
NB National Bureau of Economic Research
NRB National Resources Board
NRC National Resources Committee
SSRC Social Science Research Council
TP "Types of Economic Throey" copurse
WCM Wesley Clair Mitchell
WHDBC What Happens during Business Cycles
Subjects
Columbia University--Faculty.; National Bureau of Economic Research.; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.)--Faculty.; University of California, Berkeley--Faculty.; Beveridge, William Henry Beveridge, Baron, 1879-1963.; Clark, John Maurice, 1884-; Commons, John Rogers, 1862-1945.; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947.; Gay, Edwin F. (Edwin Francis), 1867-1946.; Hand, Learned, 1872-1961.; Hayek, Friedrich A. von (Friedrich August), 1899-1992.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Keynes, John Maynard, 1883-1946.; Lynd, Robert Staughton, 1892-1970.; Mitchell, Lucy Sprague, 1878-1967.; Taussig, F. W. (Frank William), 1859-1940.; Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929.; Economic policy.; Economics--Study and teaching.; Economics--Research.; Money.; Finance.; Anthropology.; Psychology.; Abstracts.; Articles.; Bibliographies.; Charts.; Diaries.; Drafts (documents).; Examinations; Excerpts.; First drafts.; Invitations.; Lectures.; Lists.; Notes.; Outlines.; Prefaces.; Programs.; Questionnaires.; Reviews.; Summaries.; Translations.; Economists.; College teachers.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 1-6; 15-49. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection had not restrictions.
Acquisition
1950 M-50 Widow and heirs of Wesley Clair Mitchell Gift
09/30/1998 M-98-09-30 Diaries & additional papers Connecticut, University of Gift
Gift of the widow and heirs of Prof. Mitchell, 1950.
Gift of the University of Connecticut, 1998.
- Series I: [A]. Economic Theory and its History, (8 Boxes: Boxes 1-3; 28-32)
  - 1893 November 29 hol. 16 p.; excerpt copy, 3 p; "Austrian Theory of Value"; talk to University of Chicago Philosophical Club. (Box 1)
  - 1903 August 21 hol. 3 p; Advanced Economics seminar; 1st lecture; course plans. (Box 1)
  - 1905 August [?]; hol. 3 p.; Advanced Economics, 2nd lecture; definitions of economics; Pantaleoni, Ricardo - economic man; abstract theory. (Box 1)
  - 1906 December 17 hol. 1 p.; Advanced economics examinations. (Box 1)
  - 1907 April 24 hol. 6 p.; Advanced Economics; course summary, economic man, Smith, Utilitarians, Cairnes, Marshall, Schmoller, economic methods, problem of wages. (Box 1)
  - 1907 August 20 hol. 2 p.; History of Economic Thought; lst lecture; course plans. (Box 1)
  - 1911 May 5; hol. 3 p.; Economics Seminar; Veblen’s "preconceptions". (Box 1)
  - 1912 March 28 hol. 1 p.; lecture notes; economic psychology. (Box 1)
  - 1915 October 6; hol. 2 p.; Tp; 2nd lecture; Bentham (Box 1)
  - 1913 October 3; hol. 5 p.; Tp; use of Bentham's moral arithmetic. (Box 1)
  - 1913 October 13 hol. 8 p.; Tp; 4th lecture; moral arithmetic. (Box 1)
  - 1913 October 15 hol. 1 p.; Tp; Utilitarians, Ricardo. (Box 1)
  - 1913 October 20 hol. 3 p.; Tp; 6th lecture; Ricardo’s preconceptions.; course plan outline. (Box 1)
  - 1913 December l & 3; hol. 1 p.; Tp; Ricardo and disciples. (Box 1)
  - 1913 December10, 15 & 17; hol. 9 p.; Tp; Senior’s Outline; bibliography. (Box 1)
  - 1914 January 27; hol. 1 p.; special Tp examination. (Box 1)
  - 1914 April & May; hol. 61 p.; Tp; contents list, hedonism, types of theory - hedonistic and evolutionary, course summary. (Box 1)
  - 1914 May [?]; hol. 1 p.; Tp; final lectures; problems, hedonism. (Box 1)
  - 1914 November 30 hol. 9 p.; copy excerpt 2 p.; "Classical theory of value" talk to Columbia Economics Club; WCM notes on Marx on Ricardo attached. (Box 1)
  - 1914 [?]; hol. 2 p.; Tp; introductory lecture draft (for 1915) class plans, rationality, institutions. (Box 1, Folder A435)
  - 1914 [?]; hol. 2 p.; "Use of Dewey's Social Psychology in Economic theory". (Box 1, Folder A700)
  - 1915 February 3; hol. 5 p.; Tp; 1st lecture; aim of theory; course plans; classical economics. (Box 1)
  - 1915 February 8; hol. 2 p.; Tp; Ricardo's rent theory-assumptions. (Box 1)
  - 1915 February 10; hol. 1 p.; Tp; Ricardo’s assumptions. (Box 1)
  - 1915 February 15 hol. 1 p.; Tp; 4th lecture; Ricardo’s assumptions. (Box 1)
  - 1915 February 17 hol. 3 p. [incomplete]; Tp; Ricardo's rent theory; post-Ricardian economics. (Box 1)
  - 1915 February 24 hol. 2 p.; Tp; 6th lecture; Ricardians, R. Jones, Ricardian socialists, Lloyd, Longfield. (Box 1)
  - 1915 March-May; hol. 1 p.; Tp.; list of class dates and lecture topics. (Box 1)
  - 1915 March 1st; hol. 1 p.; Tp.; Bentham, W. Thompson. (Box 1)
  - 1915 March 3; hol. 1 p.; Tp; 8th lecture; Jevons and Bentham. (Box 1)
  - 1915 March 8; hol. 1 p.; Jevons' value theory. (Box 1)
  - 1915 March 10 hol. 1 p.; Tp; Jevons - value and distribution. (Box 1)
  - 1915 March 15 hol. 1 p.; Tp; 11th lecture; Jevons and hedonism (quote), Edgeworth. (Box 1)
  - 1915 [April & May ?]; hol. 13 p.; Tp; course summary; differences between types, levels of analysis. (Box 1)
  - 1915 April 21 hol. 1 p.; Tp; lists types, Veblen's approach. (Box 1)
  - 1915 May [?]; hol. 1 p.; Tp; final lectures outline; behavior, hedonism. (Box 1)
  - 1915 May 12; hol. 3 p.; Tp; summary, hedonism and modern theory. (Box 1)
  - 1915 [?]; hol. 8 p.; Tp; economic preconceptions and Ricardo. (Box 1)
  - 1916 February—May; hol. 1 p; list of class dates and lecture topics. (Box 1)
  - 1916 February 14 hol. 9 p.; Tp; 2nd lecture; course plans, classical economics, Ricardo, J. Mill, Malthus, McCulloch, Torrens, Say, others; economic issues, money economy, natural sciences. (Box 1)
  - 1916 February 21 hol. 5 p.; Tp; 4th lecture; Ricardo's distribution; economic organization and behavior (used 11/l/l6) (Box 1)
  - 1916 February 23 hol. 5 p.; Tp; Senior, J. S. Mill (Principles), Ricardian socialists, Owen, R. Jones, Carlyle, Kingsley, Ruskin, Lloyd, Longfield, Historical School. (Box 1)
  - 1916 April 19; hol. 2 p.; Tp; pure theory - Schumpeter, Pareto, Fetter. (Box 1)
  - 1916 May 8; see 5/8/16 M. (Box 1)
  - 1916 May 10 [& earlier]; hol. 25 p.; Tp; Historical School, Schmoller’s Grundriss, value and distribution, L. Maxwell. (Box 1)
  - 1916 May 17; hol. 17 p.; Tp; Schmoller, Marx. (Box 1)
  - 1916 May 22; hol. 1 p.; Tp; Hobson’s Work and Wealth; Welfare Marshall, Davenport, Veblen, Fetter, Schmoller, Jevons, Edgeworth. (Box 1)
  - 1916 May 24; hol. 4 p.; Tp; final lecture; types, differences, hedonistic and genetic economics, institutional bases. (Box 1)
  - 1916 October 2; hol. 9 p.; Tp; 1st lecture; economic aims - reform, research, economics as science (used 10/1/17) (Box 1)
  - 1916 October 4; hol. 7 p.; Tp; Bentham & Ricardo, exact method; Wieser; Merz; English intellectual atmosphere 1809-17, politics, French Revolution. (Box 1)
  - 1916 October 9; hol. 4 p.; Tp; Bentham - life, felicific calculus. (Box 1)
  - 1916 October 11 hol. 7 p.; Tp; 4th lecture; Bentham - hedonism, criticism, social science. (Box 1)
  - 1916 October 16 hol. 11 p.; Tp; classical economics, Ricardo, Malthus, J. Mill, Torrens, McCulloch, Senior, Say, Sismondi, West, Lauderdale, Buchanan, T. Thompson, others. (Box 1)
  - 1916 October 18 [&. earlier]; hol. 15 p.; Tp; economics at universities 1800-32, WN and critics; practical interests, works on population. (Box 1)
  - 1916 October 30 hol. 1 p. [incomplete]; Tp; 9th lecture; Ricardo’s Principles. (Box 1)
  - 1916 November l; hol. 5 p.; Tp; Ricardo, Torrens. (Box 1)
  - 1916 November l; see 2/21/16 A. (Box 1)
  - 1916 November 6; hol. 18 p.; Ricardo's assumptions and abstract method, J.S. Mill. (Box 1)
  - 1916 November 7; typed & hoi. 10 p.; Tp; 12th lecture; Ricardo1 s influence and theory; quotes from Ricardo on money, profit, welfare, economic policy; Taylor on rent theory. (Box 1)
  - 1916 November 20 hol. 10 P.; Tp; 15th lecture; Jevons - life, bibliography (used 2/7 & 12/23) (Box 1)
  - 1916 November 22 hol. 5 p.; Tp; Jevons’ Theory Senior, hedonism, Jevons and Ricardo. /T/a) (Box 1)
  - 1916 November 27; hol. 8 p. ;Jevons and Bentham; attached- life of Jevons. (Box 1)
  - 1916 November 29 hol. 2 p; Tp; 18th lecture; Jevons - psychology, Theory. (Box 1)
  - 1916 December 4; hol. 1 p.; Tp; Jevons’ Theory. (Box 1)
  - 1916 December 6; hol. 5 p.; Tp; Jevons’ Theory, Walras; attached - W. Ashley quote on the marginalists (used 2/27/23 2/9/33) (Box 1)
  - 1916 December 11 hol. 8 p.; Tp; 21st lecture; Jevons and Walras. (Box 1)
  - 1916 December 13; hol. & typed 21 p.; Tp; Menger, Jevons and Walrus; attached - quotes by Davenport, Giddings and Bonor on Jevons; Walras and Menger; quotes - Walras and Menger, life of Walras. (Box 1)
  - 1916 December 13 hol. 5 p; Tp; 23d lecture; Edgeworth - life, Mathematical Psychics. (Box 1)
  - [1916 ?]; hol. 3 p.; book list. (Box 1, Folder A446)
  - [1916 ?]; typed 334 p.; Chronological list of books on economic theory and related subjects, 1776-1916 (1) 1776-1829 (2) 1830-1889 (5) 1890-1916. (Box 1)
  - 1917 January 3; hol. 6 p.; Tp; 24th lecture; Pantaleoni's Pure Economics. (Box 1)
  - 1917 January 10; see 1/10/17 M. (Box 1)
  - 1917 January 15 see 1/15/17 M. (Box 1)
  - 1917 January 17 hol. 4 p.; Tp; 28th lecture; Marshall - Principles, psychology, moneys (See Folder ?/?/17) (Box 1)
  - 19l7, January17 see 1/10/17 IS; 1/15/17 H. (Box 1)
  - 1917 January 22 hol. 5 p.; Tp; Marshall on equilibrium. (Box 1)
  - 1917 February 7; hol. 1 p.; Tp; Marshall - equilibrium, prices. (Box 1)
  - 1917 February 12 hol. 3 p.; Tp; 31st lecture; criticism of Marshall. (Box 1)
  - 1917 February 14 hol. 2 p.; Tp; Marshall - Principles, Jevons. (Box 1)
  - 1917 February 19 hol. 3 p.; Tp; Marshall - life and aims, appraisal, money, his pupils. (Box 1)
  - 1917 February 21 hol. 2 p.; Tp; 34th lecture; American economics development; attached - statistics on Germany study (used 1/14/13) (Box 1)
  - 1917 February 26 hol. 2 p.; Tp; Fetter’s Principles of Economics. (Box 1)
  - 1917 February 28 hol. 4 p; Tp; Fetter's Principles and Economic principles. (Box 1)
  - 1917 March 5; hol. 7 p.; Tp; 37th lecture; Fetter's Principles, American Psychological School; Veblen and Commons, WCM, Fisher, A. Johnson, Simons, Downey. (Box 1)
  - 1917 March 14; hol. 2 p.; Tp; Davenport's price theory. (Box 1)
  - 1917 March 21 hol. 2 p; Tp; Fetter's Economic Principles. (Box 1)
  - 1917 April 2; hol. 5 p.; Tp; pure theory and exchange - Schumpeter. (Box 1)
  - 1917 April 4; hol. 19p.; Tp; Schumpeter - criticism; attached quotes; B.M. Anderson on social value, dynamics; notes on Schumpeter’s Wesson. (Box 1)
  - 1917 April 11; hol. 3 p.; Tp; Hobson's Work and wealth; Schumpeter, Marshall, Davenport, Fetter. (Box 1)
  - 1917 April 16 hol. 7 p.[incomplete]; Tp; Hobson - criticisms. (Box 1)
  - 1917 April 30 hol. 2 p.; Tp; Marx and Schmoller. (Box 1)
  - 1917 May 14, 16; hol. 23 p.; Tp; final lectures; types listed, differences; framework for types - social behavior, reason; tests of theory, statistics. (Box 1)
  - 1917 October l; hol. 2. p.; Tp; 1st lecture; development of economics, types listed. (Box 1)
  - 1917 October l; see 10/2/16 A. (Box 1)
  - 1917 October 3; hol. 5 p.; Tp; Ricardo and post-Ricardian economics, Jevons. (Box 1)
  - 1917 October 8; hol. 6 p.; Tp; J. Mill, McCulloch, Malthus, Senior, R. Jones, Sismondi, Rosher, Knies, Leslie, W. Thompson, Whewell, Cournot, Longfield, Lloyd, Jennings, Compte, Carey, Roe, Carlyle, Ruskin, Hodskin, Bray; Ricardo and Bentham; Torrens (used 12/18/34 l/?/36) (Box 1)
  - 1917 October 8; see 12/21/20 A. (Box 1)
  - 1917 October 15 hol. 1 p.; Tp; 4th lecture; J.S. Mill, Senior, post-Ricardian economics. (Box 1)
  - 1917 October 22 hol. 3 p.; Ricardo and Jevons, Bentham and Ricardo. (Box 1)
  - [1917 ?]; hol. 23 p.; Marshall's Principles, criticism. (Box 1)
  - 1918 January 9; hol. 5 D.; Tp; Marshall - appraisal, psychology. (Box 2)
  - 1918 January 14 see 2/21/17 A. (Box 2)
  - 1918 February 13 hol. 1 p.; Tp; reading list. (Box 2)
  - 1918 March 11 hol. 3 p.; Tp; "Social value" theory. (Box 2)
  - 1918 April 2; typed 1 p.; Seminar; comparison of W. Lexis’ "Allgemeine Volkswirtschaftslehre" with Marshall and Schmoller; by Mrs. Gordon [?J (Box 2)
  - 1918 April 8; hol. 2 p.; lyres on social psychology; Veblen's Theory of Business Enterprise (used 4/15/24) (Box 2)
  - 1918 April [?]; carbon ms 2 p.; on psychological testing, Ellis. (Box 2)
  - 1918 May 15; hol. 1 p.; Tp; final lecture; theory types and economic science; war. (Box 2)
  - 1919 October 7; hol. 6 p.; Tp (New School); 1st lecture; need for theory; attitudes; course plans (used ?/?/20) (Box 2)
  - 1919 October 14; hol. 11 p.; Tp; classical economics origin; histories of theory, general English histories; English social changes; Smith and French Revolution; Malthus, Bentham. (Box 2)
  - 1919 October 21; hol. & typed 22 p.; Smith, Arthur Young, Bentham, Malthus, Lauderdale, Say, Hume, Playfair, Buchanan, Ricardo’s life and work, W, Spence, J. Mill; corn laws; Torrens, West; attached - Mallet, Smart, Brougham and Higgs on Ricardo; Mallet on Political Economy Club', bibliography; (used 11/9/20, 11/15/23 13/20/28) (Box 2)
  - 1919 October 26; hol. & typed 8 p.; Tp; Ricardian system; attached - quote by Ricardo on logical economics (used 11/22/23 12/4&6/24, U/27/28 12/4/28, 12/3/29, 11/25/30 12/5/23, 12/4&6/Z4) (Box 2)
  - 1919 November 4; hol. & -typed, 15 p. Tp. 5th lecture; Ricardo - preconceptions, social organization, rationality; Bentham and hedonism; Commons; attached - quote by Ricardo; (used 12/4/23, 12/16/24 12/11/28 12/12/29 12/9/30, 12/11/54) (Box 2)
  - 1919 December 23; hol. 1 p.; Tp; 12th lecture; Marshall - economics and behavior (used 11/11/31) (Box 2)
  - 1920 January 7; typed 1 p.; Tp; 13th lecture, hedonism - defects. (Box 2)
  - 1920 January 20; hol. & typed, 4 p.; Tp; 14th lecture; American economics - H. Carey, Dunbar, Newcombe, Walker, AEA, J.B. Clark, Patten, Fisher, Fetter; attached quotes, Constitution of AEA. (Box 2)
  - 1920 March 2; hol. 10 p.; Tp; Marx's economics and theory of history -Hegel, Darwin, Ricardo; attached –Marx’s life (Spargo) (Box 2)
  - 1920 March 16 [& earlier]; hol. 9 p.; Tp; German", and English Historical school – Rau, Hermann, Roscher, Hildebrand, Knies, Leslie, Ingram, Menger, Schmoller, J. N. Keynes, C. Hasek, Marx; history and statistics in economics - Smith, Malthus, R. Jones, Sismondi (Box 2)
  - 1920 March 30; hol. 5 p.; Tp; Veblen and Sombart, simultaneous discovery; Historical School, Marx, R. Jones. (Box 2)
  - 1920 April 20; hol. 5 p.; Tp; Hobson and marginal analysis; B. Anderson; Ehrenberg; Austrian theory - Wieser (used ?/?/23) (Box 2)
  - 1920 April 27; hol. 5 p.; Tp; review and general discussion; behaviorist viewpoint. (Box 2)
  - 1920 May 4; hol. 4 p.; Tp; final lecture; future of economics, institutional change, behavior, framework for types. (Box 2)
  - 1920 October 19; hol. & typed 12 p.; Tp; 2nd lecture; classical economics, English social and political life, agricultural revolution, industrial revolution, philanthropy, colonies, the social sciences; attached quote by S. Ronilly buying seats. (Box 2)
  - 1920 October 26; Tp; colonial system, politics, reformers, Smith and Physiocrats, social effects of WN, Bentham - French Revolution and war, Malthus. Hol. 11 p. (Box 2)
  - 1920 November 9; see 10/21/19 A. (Box 2)
  - 1920 December 12; hol. 4 p.; Tp; 9th lecture; reforms 1820-28, agitation 1812-20. (Box 2)
  - 1920 December 14; hol. 22 p.; 10th lecture; reforms 1828-32, business cycles, 1821-30, reforms - Smith, Bentham, Philosophical Radicals, Place, Ricardo, Malthus, inventions and social science (used 1/8/24, 12/20/28 3/8/29, 1/10/34) (Box 2)
  - 1920 December 21; hol. 5 p.; Tp; social sciences after Reform Bill; J. Mill, Ricardo, Cobbett, Hunt, Eddon, Sidmouth, Smith, Bentham; politics, reformers 1833-47, summary (used 1/10/24 1/15/29) (Box 2)
  - 1921 February 18; hol. 19 p.; "Price Economics in the Service of Welfare Economics"; talk to Columbia Political Economy Club. (Box 2)
  - 1921 March 8; carbon 3 p.; Tp (New School); list of students. (Box 2)
  - 1922 April 23-30; hol. 13 p.; notes on quantitative analysis; Smith and Ricardo; E. Gay. (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 3; hol. 8 p.; Tp; 1st lecture; course plans, aims of theory, economics as science (used 9/22/23 9/25/24) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 5; hol. 6 p.; Tp; A. Smith’s concepts, social science methods (used 10/2/23, 9/30/24 9/30/30) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 10; hol. 13 p.; Tp; 13th century England - politics, literature, philosophy, philanthropy, religion, science, society and economy, individual and state (used 10/11/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October l2; hol. &. typed; Tp; 4th lecture; rise of democracy and parties; attached - quote by Stanhope on 1790 Westminster agreement (used 10/4/23, 10/9/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 17; hol. 21 p.; Tp; democracy and parties, reform, local government (used 10/9/23, 10/9 & 11/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 19; hol. 13 p.; Tp; English economic problems in 18th century; Bellers, Langmens [?], Temple, Arthur Young (used 10/11/23 10/11 & 16/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 24; hol. 12 p.; Tp; 7th lecture; mercantilism decline, local governments and parliament; economic problems; attached quote by Campbell on Mansfield and common law; list of Prime Ministers 1721-1846 (used 10/16/23 10/18/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 26; hol. 10 p.; Tp; Smith - life (Rae), Hume, Moral Sentiments, Townshend, physiocrats (used 10/18/28 11/1/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 October 31 hol. 12 p.; Tp; 9th lecture; Smith - Physiocrats, WN, Carman, W. Scott (used 10/18 8c 23/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 November 2; hol. & typed 12 p.; methods - physciocrats, Smith, Veblen (preconceptions), natural sciences; W and parliament; attached quote by Smith on methods (used 10/23/25 10/25/28) (Box 2)
  - 1922 November 9; hol. 8 p.; Tp; French Revolution - R. Price, Burke, Paine, Godwin, FQX, Mackintosh, Grey; Malthus, Lauderdale, Physiocrats; attached - quote by Pitt on reform of parliament (used 10/29/29) (Box 2)
  - 1922 November 14. hol. 7 p. ;Tp; 12th lecture; population problem -Malthus (life and work), Wallace, Godwin, Franklin (used 10/30/23 10/28/30) (Box 2)
  - 1922 November 16 hol. 2 p.; Tp; Malthus and economics. (Box 2)
  - 1922 December 5; hol. 1 p.; Tp; list of class dates and lectures (used 11 & 12/23 12/7/26, 12/13/28 12/4/33) (Box 2)
  - 1922 December 14 to January23 1923 hol. 1 p.; Tp; list of class dates and lectures. (Box 2)
  - 1923 January 4; hol. 3 p.; Tp; course survey - "New Social Sciences at work" (Box 2)
  - 1923 January 5 [ & earlier]; hol. & typed 27p.; Tp; social sciences, economic history - J. Robinson, J. Maz [?]; classes; English reformers 1800-32 - Grey, Whitehead, Lambdon, Bennet, Fox, Burdett, Cochrane, Hobhouse, S. Smith, Jeffery, Horner Bingham, Simeon, Thornton, Z. Macauley, H. Moore, Wilberforce, Cartwright, Spence, Hunt, Cobbett, Attwood, Owen, Thompson, Hodskin, Sadler, Ashley; attached - quotes by and on S. Smith, Brougham, Macauley, Wilberforce. (Box 2)
  - 1923 January 25 hol. 1 p.; Tp examination. (Box 2)
  - 1923 February 7 & 12; see 12/5/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 February 8; hol. & typed 7 p.; Tp; 1st lecture; course plans, Jevons, Marshall; attached - Tp examinations (1922) (Box 2)
  - 1923 February 27 see 12/6/16 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 April 5; hol. 1 p.; Tp; Fetter - life, Principles. (Box 2)
  - 1923 September 27 see 10/3/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 October 2; see 10/5/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 October 4; see 10/12/22 A (Box 2)
  - 1923 October 9; seelO/17/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 October 11 see 10/19/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 October 16 see 10/24/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 October 23 see 10/30/22 A £ 11/2/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 October 30 see 11/14 22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 November & Dec; see 12/5/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 November 15 see 10/21/19 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 November 22 see 10/26/19 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 December 4; see 11/4/19 A. (Box 2)
  - 1923 [?]; hol. 1 p.; Tp; list of types not covered in class. (Box 2, Folder A352)
  - 1924 January 8; see 12/14/20 A. (Box 2)
  - 1924 January 10; see 12/21/20 A. (Box 2)
  - 1924 April 8; carbon 1 p.; Tp; deficiency examination. (Box 2)
  - 1924 April 15; hol. 1 p.; Tp; examination. (Box 2)
  - 1924 April 24 hol. 9 p.; Tp; Veblen and psychology - orthodox economics, Veblen's preconceptions, behaviorism. (Box 2)
  - 1924 April 25 typed 1 p.; Tp; deficiency examination. (Box 2)
  - 1924 May 16; hol. 1 p.; Tp; examination. (Box 2)
  - 1924 September 25 see 10/3/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1924 September 30 hol. 1 p.; Tp; 2nd lecture; class plans. (Box 2)
  - 1924 September 30 see 10/5/22 A. (Box 2)
  - 1924 December 4 & 6; see 10/26/19 A. (Box 2)
  - 1924 December 16 see 11/4/19 A. (Box 2)
  - 1924 December 17 hol. 8 p.; "Adam Smith"; talk to Columbia College General Honors Group. (Box 2)
  - 1925 January 6; carbon ms 3 p.; Forward to L. Edie's Economics: Principles and Problems. (Box 2)
  - 1925 January 27 mimeograph 1 p. (3 copies); Tp; examination. (Box 2)
  - 1925 March 9; hol. 3 p.; copy 3 p; "Current State of Economic Theory"; talk to Yale Economics Club. (Box 2)
  - 1925 March 14 hol. 4 p.; copy 4 p.; "Prospects of Economics"; talk at University of Chicago. (Box 2)
  - 1925 May 23; mimeograph 1 p.; carbon 1 p.; Tp; examination. (Box 2)
  - 1925 November 2; hol. 14 p.; "On the Study of the Economic Classics"; talk at Harvard Economic Seminary. (Box 2)
  - 1925 November 3; hol. 9 p.; copy 10 p.; "Economic History and Economic Theory"; lecture to E. Gay's class at Harvard. (Box 2)
  - 1926 September 28 hol. 6 p.; Tp; 1st lecture; course plans; role of economists' economics and behavior, social and natural sciences (used 9/27/28) (Box 2)